keyingredient.com 2008-12-17

# Privacy Policy | Key Ingredient

February 19, 2008

Welcome to [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient") and [ScanMyRecipes.com](http://www.scanmyrecipes.com/ "Scan My Recipes"). [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient") is a social networking service that allows cooks to preserve and share the recipes they love. [ScanMyRecipes.com](http://www.scanmyrecipes.com/ "Scan My Recipes") provides a quick and easy way to have recipes scanned, converted to electronic format, and added to your collection on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"). Both of these Web sites (the "Site(s)") are owned and operated by Key Ingredient Corporation ("Key Ingredient," "we," "us," and "our"). Key Ingredient provides the Sites and the content and services available through the Sites (collectively, the "Services") subject to our Terms of Service, which include this Online Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy explains how we protect your privacy when you use our Sites. 

**Scope of This Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy applies only to the personal information we collect through our Sites. "Personal information" means information that identifies you personally, either alone or in combination with other information available to use.

This Privacy Policy is part of and incorporated into the [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient") Terms of Service. To review the full Terms of Service, click here. 

**Your Consent to This Privacy Policy**

By accessing or using one of our Sites, you are agreeing to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy, you may not use our Services and must leave this Site immediately. 

**Questions About Our Privacy Practices**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or our Privacy Practices: 

  * Send an e-mail to [help@keyingredient.com](mailto:help@keyingredient.com "Contact Help") and write "Privacy" in the subject line
  * Write to us at: 902 E 5th Street. Suite 103. Austin. TX 78702

**This Privacy Policy May Change**

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version on the Sites. These changes will be effective as of the date we post the revised version on the Sites, but will only apply to the personal information we collect after we have posted the revised Policy on the Sites. By accessing or using one of our Sites following any such change, you are agreeing that all personal information collected from or about you through our Sites after the revised Privacy Policy is posted will be subject to the terms of the revised Privacy Policy. 

We will alert you to changes in these Terms of Service by providing a notice at the top of this page for at least 30 days after the new effective date. It is, therefore, important for you to review our Privacy Policy on a regular basis. 

This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 19, 2008.

You may access the current version of this Privacy Policy at any time by clicking on the link marked "Privacy Policy" at the bottom of each page of this Site. 

**Privacy Notices**

This Privacy Policy may be supplemented or amended from time to time by "Privacy Notices" posted on the Web pages on which we collect your personal information. Generally, Privacy Notices provide details about the personal information we collect on those pages, why we need that information, and choices you may have about the ways we use that information.

**What Personal Information Do We Collect Through Our Sites?**

There are several ways we collect personal information through our Sites:

_Information You Provide._ We collect the personal information you knowingly and voluntarily provide (about yourself and others) when you use our Sites, for example, the information you provide when you sign up to become a Member of [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"), when you create or update your Member profile on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"), and when you make a purchase on one of the Sites. 

_Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser._ We collect information that is sent to us automatically by your Web browser. This information typically includes the IP address of your Internet service provider, the name and version of your operating system, the name and version of your browser. the date and time of your visit, the address of the Web page you were visiting when you accessed our Site, and the pages you visit. Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings. 

The information provided by your browser does not identify you personally. However, we may review our server logs for security purposes, such as detecting intrusions into our network. If we suspect criminal activity, we may share our server logs – which contain visitors' IP addresses – with the appropriate investigative authorities who could use that information to trace and identify individuals. In addition, if you have created a "user identity" during one of your visits, we may link the information provided by your browser to information in our database that identifies you personally.

_Information Collected Using "Cookies" and Other Web Technologies._ We use "cookies," and similar technologies to collect information and manage and support our Services. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web server. Cookies cannot be used to install computer programs or deliver viruses to your computer. We may use two types of cookies -- "session cookies" and "persistent cookies."

A "session cookie" assigns a randomly-generated, unique identification number to your computer when you access one of our Sites. A session cookie expires after you close your browser. Generally, we use session cookies to collect information about the ways visitors use our Sites – which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page. This information is known as "click-stream information." Session cookies may also be used to facilitate your interactions with our Sites.

We may also use "persistent cookies." These cookies do not expire when you close your browser, but stay on your computer until they expire or you delete them. Each time you visit one of our Sites, our Web server will recognize you by "searching" the information contained in these cookies. By assigning your computer a persistent, unique identifier, we are able to create a database of your previous choices and preferences. This permits us to offer you a personalized experience when you use our Sites. Assigning your computer a persistent, unique identifier also helps us keep a more accurate account of how many people visit our Sites, how often they return, how their use of our Sites may vary over time, and the effectiveness of our promotional efforts.

Neither session cookies nor persistent cookies identify you personally. If, however, you have created a user identity on one of your visits to our Sites, we may link the information collected by our cookies to information that identifies you personally.

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. You may also delete our cookies as soon as you leave our Site. Although you are not required to accept our cookies when you visit our Sites, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you will not be able to use all of the features and functionality of our Sites.

In addition to cookies, we may also use "web beacons" and other web technologies to manage our Sites and email. A web beacon is a small bit of computer code. Web beacons may be used to count how many people visit a web page or tell us whether an email has been opened. We may link the information we collect using web beacons and other web technologies to information that identifies you personally.

**How Do We Use Your Personal Information?**

We may use the personal information we collect through our Sites 

  * to provide you with the information, products and services you request or purchase; 
  * for security, credit or fraud prevention purposes;
  * to provide you with efficient customer service; 
  * to provide you with a personalized experience;
  * to display personalized advertising when you visit our Sites; 
  * to contact you with special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you; 
  * to contact you with information and notices related to your use of our Services; 
  * to invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us; 
  * to better understand the your needs and interests;
  * to improve the content, functionality and usability of our Services;
  * to improve our products and services;
  * to advertise and promote our Services;
  * to improve our marketing and promotional efforts; and
  * for any other purpose we identify in a specific Privacy Notice.

_Email a Friend._ You may use our Services to send e-mail to your friends. We use the information you provide (for example, your friend's name and email address) to personalize and send your message to your friend. We do not use this information to add your friend's name or email address to our mailing lists.

**Your Content**

If you are a Member of [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient") you may be able to post, upload, transmit through or otherwise make available ("post") "Your Content" on or through the Services. As used in the Terms of Service, "Your Content" means all of the text, photographs, images, illustrations, graphics, sounds, video and audio-video clips, and other content you post on or through the Services, except Feedback, and the recopies and other information we post on your behalf when you use our recipe scanning and transcribing services. Your Content contains, but is not limited to personal information about you. To fully understand how we use Your Content, please review our Terms of Service carefully. In particular, we would like to call your attention to the following provisions in our Terms of Service: 

_You agree that by posting Your Content on or through the Services, you are granting Key Ingredient a license (a) to display advertisements in connection with Your Content and to use Your Content for advertising and promotional purposes without compensating you in anyway; (b) to make the recipes that you post on or through the Services ("Your Recipes") available to the general public through the websites and advertising networks of distribution partners and third-party service providers (including their downstream users) of Key Ingredient and its assigns; and (c) to make Your Recipes available to the general public through other media, including print and broadcast media, now known or hereafter developed. This means, for example, that one of Your Recipes (including the information and links you post on the "description," "recipe," and "about" tabs) may appear on another Web site surrounded by advertisements, together with a link to[KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"), or as part of an advertisement in a magazine. Further, you agree that by posting Your Content on or through our Services, you are granting Key Ingredient the right, with no obligation, to use your name, photograph, and geographical location (e.g. city and state) in connection with Your Recipes when Your Recipes appear or are broadcast on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"), on other Web sites or in other media as described above. If you do not want Your Recipes to be made available to the general public in any of these ways, you may "opt-out" by selecting the appropriate recipe privacy setting on your profile page on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"). If you do not want us to make your name or geographical location available to the general public in any of these ways, you may "opt-out" by selecting the appropriate privacy settings on your profile page on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"). If you do not want your photograph to be made available to the general public in any of these ways, DO NOT UPLOAD A PHOTOGRAPH to your profile page on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"). Instead, select an icon to represent you._

**Other Ways We May Share Your Personal Information**

_Service Provider._ We share personal information collected through our Sites with companies and organizations that perform services on our behalf, for example, companies that provide support services to us (such as scanning and transcription services and web hosting services) or that help us market our products and services (such as third-party e-mail marketing companies). These third parties are required by contract to use the personal information we share with them only to perform services on our behalf and to treat your personal information as strictly confidential. 

_Business Transfers._ Information collected through our Sites is an asset of Key Ingredient and will become part of our normal business records. Your personal information may be transferred to a parent, subsidiary or sister corporation of Key Ingredient or to an unrelated third party that has acquired the stock or assets of Key Ingredient, one of our affiliates, or one of our operating divisions, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, or liquidation. If such a transfer occurs, the acquiring company's use of your personal information will still be subject to this Privacy Policy and the privacy preferences you've expressed to us. In other words, the acquiring company will "step into our shoes" and use your personal information only as we would have been permitted to do under this Privacy Policy.

_Protection of Our Site and Others._ We may disclose personal information we collect through our Sites when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law (or a court order or subpoena); to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to enforce or apply our Terms of Service or other agreements; to protect the rights, property or safety of Key Ingredient, our users or others.

_As Described in a Privacy Notice._ We reserve the right to use disclose your personal information as described in any Privacy Notice posted on the Web page where you provide that information. By providing your personal information on that Web page you will be consenting to the disclosure of your personal information as described in that Privacy Notice.

**Your Choices**

When you become a Member of [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"), your initial privacy preferences will be set at our basic level – "private". You may change your privacy preferences at any time by visiting your profile page on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"). 

**Reviewing and Updating Your Profile**

You may review, correct or update your profile information at any time by visiting your profile page on [KeyIngredient.com](http://www.keyingredient.com/ "Key Ingredient"). 

**Links to Third-Party Websites**

Our Sites may contain links to third-party Web sites that are not operated by Key Ingredient. These links are provided for your reference and convenience only and do not imply any endorsement of these third-party sites nor any association with their operators. Key Ingredient does not control these sites and is not responsible for their data practices. This Privacy Policy applies only to personal information collected through our Sites. It does not apply to personal information collected on third-party Web sites. If you access other Web sites through a link on one of our Sites, please take a few minutes to review the terms of use and privacy statement posted on each Web site you visit.

**Security**

Key Ingredient has reasonable security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, unauthorized disclosure or use, or alteration of the personal information we collect through our Sites. 

Although we use reasonable measures to protect your personal information, it's important for you to understand that no Web site or database is completely secure, or "hacker proof." You can protect yourself and help us prevent computer crime by carefully guarding your password. If you believe the security of your account has been breached, please change your password immediately and notify us at [customerservice@keyingredient.com](mailto:customerservice@keyingredient.com "Contact Customer Service").

**Children**

Our Services are not directed nor targeted to children under the age of 13. We do not use our Sites to knowingly solicit personal information from or market to children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, do not provide us with any of your personal information. If we learn that someone under 13 has provided personally identifiable information through our Sites, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from our databases.

**Information for Visitors Who Access Our Sites From Outside the United States**

Key Ingredient is a U.S. corporation. Our Sites and databases may be hosted on Web servers located in the United States or other countries. Our scanning and transcribing operations are located in the United States and India, although we may at times use supplemental facilities located outside of these countries. We share the personal information we collect with our third-party service providers, and others around the world as described in this Privacy Policy. When we transfer your personal information to another country, we will take appropriate measures to protect your privacy and personal information.

Different countries have different data-protection laws, some of which provide more protection than others. By using one of our Sites, you are consenting to the transfer of your personal information to any country in the world in accordance with the terms of this Policy.
